<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fixed on Charles Houston</title>
    <link>https://cpjh.github.io/fixed/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fixed on Charles Houston</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 10:21:36 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cpjh.github.io/fixed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://cpjh.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 10:21:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpjh.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a 23 year-old PhD student in the ElectroCardioMaths Programme at Imperial College London. After graduating as the top student from my Masters undergraduate degree in Aeronautics at Imperial, including a year working as a computational aerodynamicist in Formula One, I followed my mathematical interdisciplinary interests and progressed into a research role within the university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My research is at the intersection of wide-ranging fields including computational modelling, applied mathematics and bioengineering. I feel it is best captured by the term ‘biological computation’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aim of my current work is to use advanced modelling techniques to develop high-performance, biologically-validated and cell-discrete in-silico models of phenomena observed in action potential propagation through cardiac cells. These phenomena underlie many forms of heart rhythm disturbances but are yet to be fully understood. An in-silico model would generate further insight into the mechanisms behind these features, and ultimately improve the diagnosis and medical intervention required for the effective treatment of many types of cardiac arrhythmia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have active interests in data science; how best to capture, process, analyse and present large volumes of complex data in order to transform the seemingly unintelligible into meaningful insights. I explore this field through my work with high-resolution spatiotemporal optical mapping as well as personal projects using open data sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to get in touch at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:charles.houston11@imperial.ac.uk&#34;&gt;charles.houston11@imperial.ac.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>